RÉMY GHALAYINI FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Web developer with experience in JavaScript, NodeJS, React, Gatsby, C#, .net, and Python, who builds software applications, writes machine learning algorithms, and can analyze any type of data to improve businesses. I want to help companies by creating new digital tools to attract clients, solve business problems and help them understand the power of their data. Excellent team player, problem-solver, and critical-thinker. I love programming and making things easier to use.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2021

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Globhe Drones / Stockholm

4 months contract to develop the crowddroning platform in a fast-paced and startup environment. I collaborated with business, marketing and operations staff in the design, development, testing, implementation, and production of enterprise applications.

- Raised the platform from an MVC to a mature product
- Developed new backend functionalities using node.js and firebase.
- Created new web applications in React and Gatsby with top UI/UX design
- Used Git and scrum techniques to develop digital tools with partner organizations
- Reduced decision time by 70% by introducing data analytics workflows to the team
- Expanded and used machine learning algorithms to analyse drone images

2020 - 2021

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TRAINING

Lexicon / Stockholm

Chosen after a thorough selection process to be part of a 6-month programming training. The course focuses on providing essential and modern programming skills by creating actual software products within a skilled developer team.

- Developed full-stack programs by using C# and JavaScript
- Created a modern responsive restaurant website which was ranked first in class.
- Designed web applications and embraced key UX UI concepts to enhance usability.
- Used the full power of GitHub to work within a multi-background team
- Applied OOP and MVC techniques to create powerful programs.



CONTACTS

Phone: +46 7 36 26 78 92

Email: remyghalayini@gmail.com

Website: https://rghalayini.github.io

Address: Haninge, Sweden

EDUCATION

2015

PhD IN GEOPHYSICS

Sorbonne Université / Paris

2011

MSc IN GEOSCIENCE

University of Aberdeen / UK

TRAINING

2020

SFI SWEDISH COURSE D3

Haninge Kommun

2015-2020

ONLINE COURSES IN PYTHON & MACHINE LEARNING

Columbia, Harvard and PennState Universities

WORK EXPERIENCE



2019 - 2020

DATA SCIENTIST & GEOPHYSICIST

Svenska Petroleum Exploration / London

Contracted by SPE to extract value from their complex data, provide foundation for their data-driven decisions, and train staff in visualization, storytelling, and data analysis. I have applied multiple machine learning techniques and boosted internal data competencies.

- Applied new machine learning and data analysis techniques to extract value from data
- Found new results previously unseen in old data analysis techniques.
- Influenced management to invest in Cameroon after the discovery of valuable results.
- · Attracted new investment partners through clearer communication of results.
- Trained 3 staff members in data analysis, visualization, and storytelling with data.

2016 - 2018

DATA ANALYST & PROJECT MANAGER

Petroleum Administration / Lebanon

Contracted by the Ministry of Energy to provide expert assistance in locating natural resources via data analysis and machine learning techniques. My work steered the national strategy for managing, developing, and regulating natural resource extraction in the country.

2012 - 2015

GEO-DATA ANALYST & RESEARCHER

IFP Energies Nouvelles / Paris

Three years contract with IFPEN in conjunction with my PhD focusing on research in geophysics. My work involved data collection, sorting, cleaning, exploration, modeling, interpretation of widely disparate and sparse data sets, visualization, presentation of results, and storytelling. I was also active with mentoring of students and communications.

PROJECT EXAMPLE



Globhe Drones NodeJS/Gatsby



Shopping List Node.JS/ React



Restaurant Website JavaScript/HTML



Warehouse Software C#/.NET



Python



Finance calculator Customer Segmentation K-mean clustering



Iris species prediction KNN classification



Airbnb listing analysis QlikSense



RÉMY GHALAYINI **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

EXPERTISE



Javascript / React / C# / .NET / Python / Gatsby Html / CSS SQL / NoSQL / API Machine learning / Al Azure / Firebase



Project management Agile methods / Scrum Teamwork / Collaboration



Git Visual Studio / Jupyter Adobe Suite



Swedish **English** French Arabic



GITHUB /rghalayini



TWITTER /r_ghalayini



LINKEDIN /rghalayini